PETER POTROS

+201289592850 +201551692140 peterpotros71@gmail.com Linkedin Github Kaggle Cairo, Egypt.

SUMMARY

A motivated Machine Learning engineer with skills in data preparation, exploration and building models to discover patterns in data and make predictions to answer business questions with one year experience as an AI Pro trainee at ITI.

EXPERIENCE

BI Developer at DataGear

Feb 2022 till now

Machine Learning Intern at Softec Technologies

Oct 2021 to Dec 2021

Building a graphical user application that helps users to generate probabilistic machine learning models without writing the codes using Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) and Infer.Net.

Machine Learning Intern at Omdena

Nov 2021 till now

Building NLP model that translates English data science content to Arabic

Machine Learning Intern at Machinfy

Sep 2021 to Oct 2021

Built a classification model to see whether the COVID-19 patient would die or not based on the features in the dataset.

Freelancer.com & khamsat freelancer

Oct 2020 till now

+10 completed projects with 5 stars rating.

Various projects in machine learning, data analysis and web scraping.

ONLINE COURSES

Data Scientist with Python Track (Data camp)

88 hours, 23 Courses

6 Projects, 3 Skill Assessments

Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree (Udacity)

May 2021 to Jul 2021

Learned how to build, train and tune hyperparameters for different AWS SageMaker built-in and custom machine learning models and finally deploy on a web application through endpoint using Amazon API gateway and lambda function.

Advanced data analysis Nanodegree program (Udacity)

Oct 2020 to Jan 2021

learned more python libraries like Seaborn and Matplotlib.

How to use probability and statistics methods like hypothesis testing and P_value to explore the data and find insights into it.

How to draw visualization and conclusions and finally make predictions.

Professional data analysis Nanodegree program (Udacity)

Jul 2020 to Sep 2021

Learned python programing language and most data science libraries like Numpy, Pandas and how to gather data about the problem using APIS, web scraping or from different file formats and clean it into a format one can use and fix any problems with it.

AWS Certified Data Analytics - Specialty certificate

EDUCATION

9-months Diploma of Artificial Intelligence

Information Technology Institute (ITI) and Powered by Ecole d'Ingénieurs en Informatique (EPITA)

Apr 2021 to Dec 2021

Bachelor's Degree of Petroleum Engineering (80.63%)

Faculty of Petroleum and Mining Engineering- Suez University
2013 to 2018

High School (99.2%)
Refaa secondary school, Tahta, Sohag
2011 to 2013

SKILLS

Python - SQL- NoSQL - Java - C#

Machine Learning Algorithms - Deep Learning -Probabilistic programming - Computer Vision -Natural Language Processing - Data Analysis - Data Visualization - Web Scraping - Big Data - Predictive Analytics - AB Testing

PySpark - MongoDB - PostgreSQL - Cloud AWS - SageMaker - PyTorch - SciketLearn - Keras - TensorFlow - Numpy - Pandas - Matplotlib - Seaborn - Plotly - Dash - Power BI - Apache Spark - RESTful API - Linux - BeautifulSoup – Selenium

Problem-solving - Time-Management - Teamwork - Self-management

Volunteering

IT Member

Society of Petroleum Engineers (SPE) Suez University Student chapter

Sep 2016 to Jun 2017

Participated in the development of the SPE Suez website using WordPress. Created a website showing projects of my department colleagues.

Received two best member awards.

LANGUAGES

Arabic Native English Very good

PORJECTS

Probabilistic Programming application

Developed a desktop application which allows users to draw the probabilistic machine learning model they want graphically and then it generates the infer.Net code for this model.

COVID-19 Case Surveillance Public Use Data

Responsible for building a classification model to see whether the COVID-19 patient died or not based on the features in the dataset using random forest classifier and deep learning.

NLP to Translate Data Science Content into Arabic

Using Machine Translation and transformer models to Translate English Data Science Content into Arabic.

Web service for "Wuzzuf Jobs" dataset.

Using Java for data exploration and building machine learning model for "Wuzzuf_Jobs" dataset using smile library and KMeans unsupervised algorithm and deploy it on web service using spring framework.

Sentiment Analysis Web App Using PyTorch and AWS SageMaker

Built end-to-end Sentiment Analysis model and Deployed the trained model on a web app and accessing our model endpoint using Lambda function.

Plagiarism Detection using AWS SageMaker

Built a machine learning model to examine a text file and performs binary classification; labeling that file as either *plagiarized* or *not*, depending on how similar that text file is to a provided source text.

Seoul Bike Rental Prediction 8th/110 (Kaggle Competition)

Predicting the total count of bikes rented during each, using only information available prior to the rental period using time series techniques.

Car Crashes' Severity Prediction 35th/138 (Kaggle Competition)

predicting the severity of the crash out of 4 levels based on information about the environment of the car crash.

Data analysis using Twitter API

gathered the data from the dogs_rates Twitter account using Twitter API which displays the doges' pics and their reviews, then wrangled these data from missing and incorrect data to explore them and made data visualization of the results.